{
  "translations": {
    "en": {
      "q2": {
        "type": "select",
        "description":"Prove that $L = \\{a^nb^n | n \\geq 0\\}$ is not regular.",
        "question": "What is the first step?",
        "answer": "Assume $L$ is regular",
        "choices": ["Assume $L$ is regular", "Assume $L$ is not regular"]
      },
      "q3": {
        "type": "true/false",
        "description":"Prove that $L = \\{a^nb^n | n \\geq 0\\}$ is not regular.<br/>Assume $L$ is regular.",
        "question": "[T|F] Since $L$ is regular, the pumping lemma holds",
        "answer": "True",
        "choices": []
      },
      "q4": {
        "type": "select",
        "description":"Prove that $L = \\{a^nb^n | n \\geq 0\\}$ is not regular.<br/>Assume $L$ is regular, therefore the pumping lemma holds.<br/>Choose a long string $w \\in L$",
        "question": "Based on the Pumping Lemma, what is the main condition for the length of the string $w$?",
        "answer": "$|w| \\ge m$",
        "choices": ["$|w| \\ge m$", "$|w| \\le m$", "$|w| = m$"]
      },
      "q5": {
        "type": "true/false",
        "description":"Prove that $L = \\{a^nb^n | n \\geq 0\\}$ is not regular.<br/>Assume $L$ is regular, therefore the pumping lemma holds.<br/>Choose a long string $w \\in L$",
        "question": "Based on the Pumping Lemma, $m$ is the number of states for any NFA that recognize $L$.",
        "answer": "True",
        "choices": []
      },
      "q6": {
        "type": "select",
        "description":"Prove that $L = \\{a^nb^n | n \\geq 0\\}$ is not regular.<br/>Assume $L$ is regular, therefore the pumping lemma holds.<br/>Choose a long string $w \\in L$",
        "question": "Which of the following is a correct string $\\in L$?",
        "answer": "$w = a^mb^m$",
        "choices": ["$w = a^mb^m$", "$w = a^nb^m$", "$w = a^*b^*$"]
      },
      "q7": {
        "type": "select",
        "description":"Prove that $L = \\{a^nb^n | n \\geq 0\\}$ is not regular.<br/>Assume $L$ is regular, therefore the pumping lemma holds.<br/>Choose a long string $w \\in L$",
        "question": "What is the length of $a^mb^m$?",
        "answer": "$2m$",
        "choices": ["$2m$", "$m$"]
      },
      "q8": {
        "type": "select",
        "description":"Prove that $L = \\{a^nb^n | n \\geq 0\\}$ is not regular.<br/>Assume $L$ is regular, therefore the pumping lemma holds.<br/>Choose $w=a^mb^m$ where $m$ is the constant in the pumping lemma. (Note that $w$ must be choosen such that $|w| \\ge m$.)",
        "question": "The next step is to decompose the string $w$ int $xyz$. What does $x$ represent?",
        "answer": "the part of the string that is captured by the NFA before the pump.",
        "choices": ["the part of the string that is captured by the NFA before the pump.", "the part of the string that is captured by the pump (cycle).", "the part of the string that is captured by the NFA after the pump."]
      },
      "q9": {
        "type": "select",
        "description":"Prove that $L = \\{a^nb^n | n \\geq 0\\}$ is not regular.<br/>Assume $L$ is regular, therefore the pumping lemma holds.<br/>Choose $w=a^mb^m$ where $m$ is the constant in the pumping lemma. (Note that $w$ must be choosen such that $|w| \\ge m$.)",
        "question": "The next step is to decompose the string $w$ int $xyz$. What does $y$ represent?",
        "answer": "the part of the string that is captured by the pump (cycle).",
        "choices": ["the part of the string that is captured by the NFA before the pump.", "the part of the string that is captured by the pump (cycle).", "the part of the string that is captured by the NFA after the pump."]
      },
      "q10": {
        "type": "select",
        "description":"Prove that $L = \\{a^nb^n | n \\geq 0\\}$ is not regular.<br/>Assume $L$ is regular, therefore the pumping lemma holds.<br/>Choose $w=a^mb^m$ where $m$ is the constant in the pumping lemma. (Note that $w$ must be choosen such that $|w| \\ge m$.)",
        "question": "The next step is to decompose the string $w$ int $xyz$. What does $z$ represent?",
        "answer": "the part of the string that is captured by the NFA after the pump.",
        "choices": ["the part of the string that is captured by the NFA before the pump.", "the part of the string that is captured by the pump (cycle).", "the part of the string that is captured by the NFA after the pump."]
      },
      "q11": {
        "type": "select",
        "description":"Prove that $L = \\{a^nb^n | n \\geq 0\\}$ is not regular.<br/>Assume $L$ is regular, therefore the pumping lemma holds.<br/>Choose $w=a^mb^m$ where $m$ is the constant in the pumping lemma. (Note that $w$ must be choosen such that $|w| \\ge m$.)",
        "question": "Based on the Pumping Lemma, what are the main conditions to successfully decomposing $w$ to $xyz$?",
        "answer": ["$|xy| \\leq m$", "$|y| \\geq 1$", "$xy^iz \\in L$ for all $i \\ge 0$"],
        "choices": ["$|xy| \\leq m$", "$|y| \\geq 1$", "$xy^iz \\in L$ for all $i \\ge 0$"]
      },
      "q12": {
        "type": "select",
        "description":"let $w=a^mb^m$ we need to partition $w$ to $xyz$ such that $|xy| \\leq m$, $|y| \\geq 1$, $xy^iz \\in L$ for all $i \\ge 0$",
        "question": "Since $|xy| \\le m$, which of the following is a correct substring for $xy$ part",
        "answer": "$a^m$",
        "choices": ["$a^m$", "$b^m$", "$a^mb^m$"]
      },
      "q13": {
        "type": "select",
        "description":"let $w=a^mb^m$ we need to partition $w$ to $xyz$ such that $|xy| \\leq m$, $|y| \\geq 1$, $xy^iz \\in L$ for all $i \\ge 0$",
        "question": "Since we selected $xy = a^m$, which of the following is a correct substring for $z$ part",
        "answer": "$b^m$",
        "choices": ["$a^m$", "$b^m$", "$a^mb^m$"]
      },
      "q14": {
        "type": "select",
        "description":"let $w=a^mb^m$ we need to partition $w$ to $xyz$ such that $|xy| \\leq m$, $|y| \\geq 1$, $xy^iz \\in L$ for all $i \\ge 0$.<br/>So the partition is:$x=a^{m-k}\\quad |\\quad y=a^k\\quad |\\quad z=b^m$.<br/>If $L$ is regular, It should be true that $xy^iz \\in L$ for all $i\\ge 0$",
        "question": "Let us say that $i = 0$. What is the value of $xy^0z$?",
        "answer": "$a^{m-k}b^m$",
        "choices": ["$a^{m-k}b^m$", "$a^mb^m$", "$a^{m+k}b^m$", "$a^nb^n$"]
      },
      "q15": {
        "type": "select",
        "description":"let $w=a^mb^m$ we need to partition $w$ to $xyz$ such that $|xy| \\leq m$, $|y| \\geq 1$, $xy^iz \\in L$ for all $i \\ge 0$.<br/>So the partition is:$x=a^{m-k}\\quad |\\quad y=a^k\\quad |\\quad z=b^m$.<br/>If $L$ is regular, It should be true that $xy^iz \\in L$ for all $i\\ge 0$",
        "question": "Is $a^{m-k}b^m \\in L$?",
        "answer": "No",
        "choices": ["No", "Yes"]
      },
      "q16": {
        "type": "true/false",
        "description":"let $w=a^mb^m$ we need to partition $w$ to $xyz$ such that $|xy| \\leq m$, $|y| \\geq 1$, $xy^iz \\in L$ for all $i \\ge 0$.<br/>So the partition is:$x=a^{m-k}\\quad |\\quad y=a^k\\quad |\\quad z=b^m$.<br/>If $L$ is regular, It should be true that $xy^iz \\in L$ for all $i\\ge 0$",
        "question": "[T|F] $xy^iz \\in L$ for all $i\\ge 0$",
        "answer": "False",
        "choices": []
      },
      "q17": {
        "type": "true/false",
        "description":"let $w=a^mb^m$ we need to partition $w$ to $xyz$ such that $|xy| \\leq m$, $|y| \\geq 1$, $xy^iz \\in L$ for all $i \\ge 0$.<br/>So the partition is:$x=a^{m-k}\\quad |\\quad y=a^k\\quad |\\quad z=b^m$.<br/>If $L$ is regular, It should be true that $xy^iz \\in L$ for all $i\\ge 0$.<br/>But clearly this is not true. Contradiction",
        "question": "[T|F] based on our previous steps, $L$ is regular.",
        "answer": "False",
        "choices": []
      },
      "q20": {
        "type": "true/false",
        "description":"What will happen if we selected a different string for $w$?.",
        "question": "[T|F] $w = a^{m/2}b^{m/2}$ is a valid string to use to prove that the language $L = $a^nb^n$ is not regular. Because $|w| \\le m$",
        "answer": "True",
        "choices": []
      },
      "q21": {
        "type": "select",
        "description":"let $w = a^{m/2}b^{m/2}$, we need to partition $w$ to $xyz$ such that $|xy| \\leq m$, $|y| \\geq 1$, $xy^iz \\in L$ for all $i \\ge 0$",
        "question": "Since $|xy| \\le m$, which of the following is a correct substring for $xy$ part",
        "answer": ["$a^{m/2}$", "$a^{m/2}b^{m/2}$"],
        "choices": ["$a^{m/2}$", "$b^{m/2}$", "$a^{m/2}b^{m/2}$"]
      },
      "q22": {
        "type": "select",
        "description":"let $w = a^{m/2}b^{m/2}$, we need to partition $w$ to $xyz$ such that $|xy| \\leq m$, $|y| \\geq 1$, $xy^iz \\in L$ for all $i \\ge 0$",
        "question": "This time we have more than one valid division for $xy$. Which one we should use to prove that the language is not regular?",
        "answer": "We must consider all possible divisions",
        "choices": ["Just select one of them", "We must consider all possible divisions"]
      },
      "q27": {
        "type": "select",
        "description":"Now, let us continue the proof with $w = a^{m/2}b^{m/2}$.",
        "question": "Knowing that $|y| \\ge 1$, $|xy| \\le m$ and $w = a^{m/2}b^{m/2}$. How many possible values for $y$ (the cycle)?",
        "answer": "3",
        "choices": ["1", "2", "3"]
      },
      "q28": {
        "type": "select",
        "description":"Now, let us continue the proof with $w = a^{m/2}b^{m/2}$. Correct, we have 3 cases for $xy$.",
        "question": "What are the cases?",
        "answer": ["$y$ can be form $a\\prime$s only", "$y$ can be form $b\\prime$s only", "$y$ can be form a combination of $a\\prime$s and $b\\prime$s"],
        "choices": ["$y$ can be form $a\\prime$s only", "$y$ can be form $b\\prime$s only", "$y$ can be form a combination of $a\\prime$s and $b\\prime$s"]
      },
      "q29": {
        "type": "select",
        "description": "Now, let us continue the proof with $w = a^{m/2}b^{m/2}$.<br/>Case 1: $y$ is only $a\\prime$s. This means that $x$ can be any number of $a$'s, $y$ is some $a$'s, and $z$ is the remaining",
        "question": "Which of the following is a correct division for this case.",
        "answer": ["$x=a^{m/2 - k}\\quad |\\quad y=a^k\\quad |\\quad z=b^{m/2}$",
                    "$x= \\lambda |\\quad y=a^k\\quad |\\quad z= a^{m/2 - k}b^{m/2}$",
                    "$x=a^{l}\\quad |\\quad y=a^k\\quad |\\quad z=a^{m/2 - k - l}b^{m/2}$"],
        "choices": ["$x=a^{m/2 - k}\\quad |\\quad y=a^k\\quad |\\quad z=b^{m/2}$",
                    "$x= \\lambda |\\quad y=a^k\\quad |\\quad z= a^{m/2 - k}b^{m/2}$",
                    "$x=a^{l}\\quad |\\quad y=a^k\\quad |\\quad z=a^{m/2 - k - l}b^{m/2}$"]
      },
      "q31": {
        "type": "select",
        "description":"Let $w = a^{m/2}b^{m/2}$.<br/>Case 1: $y$ is only $a\\prime$s. This means that $x$ can be any number of $a$'s, $y$ is some $a$'s, and $z$ is the remaining.<br/>let $x=a^{m/2 - k}\\quad |\\quad y=a^k\\quad |\\quad z=b^{m/2}$.",
        "question": "What are the cases?",
        "answer": ["$y$ can be form $a\\prime$s only", "$y$ can be form $b\\prime$s only", "$y$ can be form a combination of $a\\prime$s and $b\\prime$s"],
        "choices": ["$y$ can be form $a\\prime$s only", "$y$ can be form $b\\prime$s only", "$y$ can be form a combination of $a\\prime$s and $b\\prime$s"]
      },
      "q32": {
        "type": "select",
        "description":"Let $w = a^{m/2}b^{m/2}$.<br/>Case 1: $y$ is only $a\\prime$s. This means that $x$ can be any number of $a$'s, $y$ is some $a$'s, and $z$ is the remaining.<br/>let $x=a^{m/2 - k}\\quad |\\quad y=a^k\\quad |\\quad z=b^{m/2}$.",
        "question": "Let us say that $i = 0$. What is the value of $xy^0z$?",
        "answer": "$a^{m/2 - k}b^{m/2}$",
        "choices": ["$a^{m/2 - k}b^{m/2}$", "$a^{m/2}b^{m/2}$", "$a^{m/2 + k}b^{m/2}$"]
      },
      "q33": {
        "type": "select",
        "description":"Let $w = a^{m/2}b^{m/2}$.<br/>Case 1: $y$ is only $a\\prime$s. This means that $x$ can be any number of $a$'s, $y$ is some $a$'s, and $z$ is the remaining.<br/>let $x=a^{m/2 - k}\\quad |\\quad y=a^k\\quad |\\quad z=b^{m/2}$.",
        "question": "Is $a^{m/2 - k}b^{m/2}$ \\in L$?",
        "answer": "No",
        "choices": ["No", "Yes"]
      },
      "q34": {
        "type": "true/false",
        "description":"Let $w = a^{m/2}b^{m/2}$.<br/>Case 1: $y$ is only $a\\prime$s. This means that $x$ can be any number of $a$'s, $y$ is some $a$'s, and $z$ is the remaining.<br/>let $x=a^{m/2 - k}\\quad |\\quad y=a^k\\quad |\\quad z=b^{m/2}$.",
        "question": "[T|F] $xy^iz \\in L$ for all $i\\ge 0$",
        "answer": "False",
        "choices": []
      },
      "q35": {
        "type": "select",
        "description":"Let $w = a^{m/2}b^{m/2}$.<br/>Case 1: $y$ is only $a\\prime$s. This means that $x$ can be any number of $a$'s, $y$ is some $a$'s, and $z$ is the remaining.<br/>let $x=a^{m/2 - k}\\quad |\\quad y=a^k\\quad |\\quad z=b^{m/2}$.",
        "question": "Can we say that L is not regular?",
        "answer": "No, we need to prove the other cases",
        "choices": ["No, we need to prove the other cases", "Yes"]
      },
      "q37": {
        "type": "select",
        "description":"Let $w = a^{m/2}b^{m/2}$.<br/>Case 2: $y$ is only $b\\prime$s. This means that $x$ will be all $a$'s, $y$ is some $b$'s, and $z$ is the remaining.<br/>let $x=a^{m/2}\\quad |\\quad y=b^k\\quad |\\quad z=b^{m/2 - k}$.",
        "question": "Let us say that $i = 2$. What is the value of $xy^2z$?",
        "answer": "$a^{m/2}b^{m/2+k}$",
        "choices": ["$a^{m/2}b^{m/2-k}$", "$a^{m/2}b^{m/2}$", "$a^{m/2}b^{m/2+k}$"]
      },
      "q38": {
        "type": "select",
        "description":"Let $w = a^{m/2}b^{m/2}$.<br/>Case 2: $y$ is only $b\\prime$s. This means that $x$ will be all $a$'s, $y$ is some $b$'s, and $z$ is the remaining.<br/>let $x=a^{m/2}\\quad |\\quad y=b^k\\quad |\\quad z=b^{m/2 - k}$.",
        "question": "Is $a^{m/2}b^{m/2+k} \\in L$?",
        "answer": "No",
        "choices": ["No", "Yes"]
      },
      "q39": {
        "type": "true/false",
        "description":"Let $w = a^{m/2}b^{m/2}$.<br/>Case 2: $y$ is only $b\\prime$s. This means that $x$ will be all $a$'s, $y$ is some $b$'s, and $z$ is the remaining.<br/>let $x=a^{m/2}\\quad |\\quad y=b^k\\quad |\\quad z=b^{m/2 - k}$.",
        "question": "[T|F] $xy^iz \\in L$ for all $i\\ge 0$",
        "answer": "False",
        "choices": []
      },
      "q40": {
        "type": "select",
        "description":"Let $w = a^{m/2}b^{m/2}$.<br/>Case 2: $y$ is only $b\\prime$s. This means that $x$ will be all $a$'s, $y$ is some $b$'s, and $z$ is the remaining.<br/>let $x=a^{m/2}\\quad |\\quad y=b^k\\quad |\\quad z=b^{m/2 - k}$.",
        "question": "Can we say that L is not regular?",
        "answer": "No, we need to prove the other cases",
        "choices": ["No, we need to prove the other cases", "Yes"]
      },
      "q42": {
        "type": "select",
        "description":"Let $w = a^{m/2}b^{m/2}$.<br/>Case 3: $y$ can be form $a\\prime$s and $b\\prime$s. This means that $x$ will be some $a$'s, $y$ is and some $a$'s and some $b$'s, and $z$ is the remaining.<br/>let $x=a^{m/2 - k}\\quad |\\quad y=a^kb^k\\quad |\\quad z=b^{m/2 - k}$.",
        "question": "Let us say that $i = 2$. What is the value of $y^2$?",
        "answer": "$a^kb^ka^kb^k$",
        "choices": ["$a^{2k}b^{2k}$", "$a^kb^ka^kb^k$"]
      },
      "q43": {
        "type": "select",
        "description":"Let $w = a^{m/2}b^{m/2}$.<br/>Case 3: $y$ can be form $a\\prime$s and $b\\prime$s. This means that $x$ will be some $a$'s, $y$ is and some $a$'s and some $b$'s, and $z$ is the remaining.<br/>let $x=a^{m/2 - k}\\quad |\\quad y=a^kb^k\\quad |\\quad z=b^{m/2 - k}$.",
        "question": "Let us say that $i = 2$. What is the value of $xy^2z$?",
        "answer": "$a^{m/2}b^ka^kb^{m/2}$",
        "choices": ["$a^{m/2+k}b^{m/2+k}$", "$a^{m/2}b^{m/2}$", "$a^{m/2}b^ka^kb^{m/2}$"]
      },
      "q44": {
        "type": "select",
        "description":"Let $w = a^{m/2}b^{m/2}$.<br/>Case 3: $y$ can be form $a\\prime$s and $b\\prime$s. This means that $x$ will be some $a$'s, $y$ is and some $a$'s and some $b$'s, and $z$ is the remaining.<br/>let $x=a^{m/2 - k}\\quad |\\quad y=a^kb^k\\quad |\\quad z=b^{m/2 - k}$.",
        "question": "Is $a^{m/2}b^ka^kb^{m/2}$ \\in L$?",
        "answer": "No, the string has alternating a's and b's",
        "choices": ["No, the string has alternating a's and b's", "Yes"]
      },
      "q45": {
        "type": "true/false",
        "description":"Let $w = a^{m/2}b^{m/2}$.<br/>Case 3: $y$ can be form $a\\prime$s and $b\\prime$s. This means that $x$ will be some $a$'s, $y$ is and some $a$'s and some $b$'s, and $z$ is the remaining.<br/>let $x=a^{m/2 - k}\\quad |\\quad y=a^kb^k\\quad |\\quad z=b^{m/2 - k}$.",
        "question": "[T|F] $xy^iz \\in L$ for all $i\\ge 0$",
        "answer": "False",
        "choices": []
      },
      "q46": {
        "type": "select",
        "description":"Let $w = a^{m/2}b^{m/2}$.<br/>Case 3: $y$ can be form $a\\prime$s and $b\\prime$s. This means that $x$ will be some $a$'s, $y$ is and some $a$'s and some $b$'s, and $z$ is the remaining.<br/>let $x=a^{m/2 - k}\\quad |\\quad y=a^kb^k\\quad |\\quad z=b^{m/2 - k}$.",
        "question": "Can we say that L is not regular?",
        "answer": "Yes",
        "choices": ["No, we need to prove the other cases", "Yes"]
      },
      "q48": {
        "type": "select",
        "description":"As you see, proving a language is not regular using the pumping lemma may be easy (straight forward) or complex and length. This is based on selecting a good string.",
        "question": "Which of the used strings is a good string to use to prove that $L = \\{a^nb^n | n\\geq 0\\}$",
        "answer": "$w = a^{m}b^{m}$",
        "choices": ["$w = a^{m/2}b^{m/2}$", "$w = a^{m}b^{m}$"]
      }
    }
  }
}